Kar Do,
in the case of Kishore Kumar, more and more cases are coming to light day by day. It is
possible that you are
taking health insurance policies
but do you know about such insurance
policies which are specially
designed for Kabir? Hello, I am
Ritu Sharma and you are watching video.com and
today I will tell you about the Covid insurance
policy and how the Kovid Dens
Forest policy is
different from the normal health insurance policy. There are
two
types of policies available in the market regarding Covid policies. The first is the Corner
Khabar policy and the second is the Corona Rakshak policy which is the
Corona Kavach policy, which is an indemnity policy, that is,
if your expenditure is Rs 1 lakh
then you will get the additional cover. If your
expenditure is Rs 2 lakh then you will get Rs 2 lakh. Whereas in the
Corona Rakshak policy, it does
not matter
how much you have spent, whatever amount you had
taken the policy for, you will get the entire amount
in one go. So, if your expenditure is Rs 1
and you have taken a policy of Rs 2 lakh then
you will get the entire cover.  You will get up to Rs. 1 lakh. The
biggest difference between the Corona Kavach and Corona Rakshak policies is
that you will get cover under the Corona Cover policy only if
you are hospitalized for a minimum of one day. Keep in
mind that if you are
taking medicines at home, then the
full cover policy does not provide any coverage.
However, in the Corona Rakshak policy,
you must be
hospitalized for a minimum of three days. After three days of
hospitalization, you will be given all the
expenses. However, if
you are hospitalized for less than three days, then
you are not given any cover under the Rakshak policy.
This is the biggest difference between the two policies.
Now, the biggest question in your mind will be that
if you are hospitalized for one day,
but your medicines
and other expenses will continue for 10 to 12 days
after that, then will the
cover for these expenses be included in these cards?
You have the former Raksha policy, which will definitely
give you the entire amount after three days of hospitalization.
But the special thing about the Corona Kavach policy is
that  It covers all expenses from 15 days before your illness till
30 days after the date of your hospitalization. Let us
understand this with an example. Suppose you are hospitalized on December 1st, then
all your
expenses from November 15th to
December 1st and the 30 days after December 1st, all those
expenses will be given to you in pre and
post insurance here. Now a question
arises here that will the
expenses of other diseases be covered in Corona insurance policies?
If the expenses of any of your other
diseases are high due to Corona, such as you
also have BP or diabetes, and if their expenses are
high, these diseases are
due to quality, then will this be
covered in the World Insurance policy? The answer
is absolutely, it will be covered in the Corona insurance policy.
Now let us know
how much amount of cover is given to you in these policies. The
Corona cover policy is here,
you can get a minimum cover of Rs 50 thousand and a maximum
cover of Rs 5 lakh. In this, you
can select the amount in multiples of 50,000, such as  56001 lakh 1.5 lakh 2
lakh By doing this you can take a maximum cover of up to 5 lakhs
but keep in mind that
if in the meantime you go to an expensive hospital
where your expenses
exceed 5 lakhs, then in the Rona Kavach policy
you get cover of only up to 5 lakhs,
more than this amount does not give you immediate quality, in the
Corner Rakshak policy
you can take recovery for a minimum of 50 thousand and a maximum of
2.5 lakh rupees and
this cover is given to you at one go, now let us
tell you for how long you
can take the policy, this is the tenure of the policy, you
can choose a minimum of three and a half months, six and a half months and up to nine and a half months, this
more demand has been kept because here the
15 day period is a meeting period, that is,
if you have any defect on 1st December,
you get admitted on 5th December
and you come out on 10th December, then
in such a condition you will not be given any kind of
cover because if seen,
till 15 days before hospitalization  If
you had not taken any such policy, then there is a
waiting period of 15 days
in this policy. This is done so that there is
no fraud with the company. Now the question arises that can they
get this information, then all the people from 18 years to 65
years can get the Gaon
Insurance Policy,
what information will you get in it, in this
all your small and big expenses related to Corona, that is, the
expenses of top clubs of PPP, your bed, ICU, all of them are covered.
Now the question arises that if you have taken Sajan Health
Insurance Policy, then is the
Corona expense covered in it, then the
answer is absolutely yes, the expenses incurred by you are
covered in health insurance,
but then what is the need to take any other foreign policy, this is
because the
Confidence Policy, especially the Corona Kavach
Policy, covers all the expenses incurred 15
days before the hospitalization and three days after the hospitalization,
whether they are small or big, that is, all the
expenses related to the disease are
completely covered up and  This will give you hope,
you would have liked the information shown in the video,
if you liked it then please like,
share and give us your opinion by commenting,
keep watching Bhains and Com for such information and do not forget to
subscribe to Zee Business from all platforms,
Namaste A